# Amritpreet Singh

Cape Girardeau, MO 63701

**J** 573-200-1100 ■ amritpreet98@gmail.com 📠 amritpreet98 👩 github.com/mraps98

mraps98.github.io/portfolio

## Personal Statement

I am a passionate full stack web and mobile developer with a Master's in Applied Computer Science. I have experience with emerging technologies/practices like GraphQL, React Native, Firebase, .NetCore 5, Tailwind, Redux, Thunks, Asynchronous design, Design Patterns, Lazy loading, NextJS SSR, SSG, Latex, Git, AWS (Deployment and DB), Encryption, Hashing, Data Structures, role-based access, responsive design, test-driven development, mobile first approach, SQL, NoSQL and

I believe in not sticking to one language and love exploring C, C++, Flutter, Python Flask, Java Spring, Android Kotlin/Java, Apple Swift, Ruby. I am able to adapt to changes in the development workflow/languages/frameworks as it is a critical and scalable skill.

I believe team work is critical for success and am able to work well with individuals with a broad range of traits. I am able to deduce business decisions and solutions rapidly and independently. I believe an eager-to-learn attitude is the only way forward and that drives me.

#### Technical Skills

Languages: C#, JavaScript, Python, Java, C, HTML/CSS, SQL, Bash, Batch, TypeScript Technologies/Practices: .NET Core, React, React Native, Redux, SCSS, Linux, Firebase, AWS, Flask, Node, Jest, Git,

NextJS, MongoDB, REST APIs, Material UI, Tailwind, Responsive Design, Design Patterns, esLint, TDD, Linux, VIM

# Experience

Element 74 May 2021 - Present

SaaS Application Developer

Cape Girardeau, MO

- Developed a responsive, single page patient management application using .NET Core, Firebase, Material UI, React and Redux including appointment scheduling, instant messaging, patient dashboards, role-based access and realtime push notifications.
- Developed an innovative, responsive single page e-commerce application using React, Firebase, SCSS and TypeScript including Strip integration and Shippo API integration for letting customers choose their preferred shipping carriers and methods including shipping to 9 U.S. territories.

#### Southeast Missouri State University

Aug. 2020 - May 2021

 $Graduate\ Assistant$ 

Cape Girardeau, MO

- Developed an open source C library for efficient tensor computations, decomposition and storage.
- Developed an automated grading system for student homeworks using Python.
- Developed a user-friendly Conversation Recommendation System (Chatbot) to answer prospective and current students' questions about the program.
- Assisted with teaching Assembly Language, Boolean Algebra and Logic Gates for Computer Architecture.

IPE Global June 2018 - Aug. 2018

I.T. and E-governance Intern

New Delhi, India

- Developed a project management system for the UP State Government using PHP CodeIgniter and MySQL.
- Gave a presentation to the client (UP State Government) at 18 years old.

#### Education

## Southeast Missouri State University (3.9GPA)

Aug. 2019 - May 2022

Master of Applied Computer Science

Aug. 2016 - May 2019

Webster University (3.66GPA)

St. Louis, MO

Cape Girardeau, MO

Bachelor of Computer Science

#### Relevant Coursework

- Data Structures
- UI/UX

- Artificial Intelligence
- Operating Systems

- Web Development
- Database Management
- Machine Learning
- Computer Architecture

StockHaus | React, TypeScript, Firebase, SCSS

May 2021

- Developed a fully responsive e-commerce application using React, TypeScript, Firebase and SCSS.
- Utilized firebase for user authentication with role-based access.
- Implemented a full-featured, responsive admin panel (React, SCSS, Firebase) to add and modify product and discounts.
- Implemented abstract interfaces and static type checking using Typescript.

## Algos | .NET Core, React, Firebase

May 2021

- Developed a fully responsive patient management application for clients using React, Redux, .NET Core, Firebase and MSSQL.
- Implemented realtime push notifications for Doctors when patients submit forms using Firebase.
- Used Task Scheduler to send SMS to patients to check up on them periodically and store their pain scores.
- Implemented an interactive conversational system between Patients and the system via SMS using Twilio.
- Implemented Redux and Redux thunks for state management and asynchronous api calls between components.
- Implemented Material UI for an attractive user experience.
- Implemented lazy loading components, React Suspense and react-router for an efficient routing system.
- Implemented authorization with role-based access, JWT Tokens, two factor authentication and resetting passwords.

## MIS For UPPPTDP | PHP, MySQL

August 2018

- Developed a project management system for the UP state government tourism office to support pro-poor tourism.
- Gave a presentation to the client (UP State Government) at 18 years old.

# Leadership / Extracurricular

## **ACM Chapter SEMO**

Aug. 2020 - May 2021

Secretary

Southeast Missouri State University

• Maintained the chapter's primary website.

## Webster University Student Government Organization

May. 2018 – December 2018

Webster University Thailand

Treasurer

• Maintained the funds for the Student Government Association.

## Rotaract Club of Webster Bangkok

Jan. 2017 – December 2018

Treasurer

Webster University Thailand

Maintained the funds for the Rotaract Club of Webster Bangkok.